Gold and silver prices are peaking
right now. So, here to share tips and
information about what is worth selling,
we welcome back antique appraiser Gary
Germer. Gary, great to see you. Happy
Monday. >> You, too. Thank you for having
me. >> week. It's kind of lots of
things, lots of buzz, people busy.
>> Everyone's running different directions
and and it's great. >> Tell me about
the idea that silver is really um
really kind of incredible right now, the
prices. >> Yeah, when Tammy,
the producer and I were talking,
um you know, we've talked touched on the
idea of of gold and silver in the past,
but I really want to focus because it's
at all-time highs. Silver especially has
jumped 138%
since April. It went
from $29 and it was $68.
>> How does that happen? Do you know the
reason for that? >> Um well, I'm not an
economist, but I have read on this trying
to figure it out myself and there's a
couple things. One of the main things
that pushes the the uh commodities market
for gold and silver >> Right. >> is uh
instability in the overall market. So,
who's buying it are banks and governments.
>> Okay. >> And so, they're worried
and I think the the theory is with the
the tariffs on and off, it's created a
sense of instability. And so, people
are moving into something solid. Silver
also is being used industrially for um
uh solar panels and in that industry
and stuff like that. >> interesting.
Okay. >> a lot of there's a lot of uh
there's a number of factors, but that's
my understanding is that the dollar is
really low right now and so,
people are going to secure
and gold and silver are secure commodities.
>> So, I know a number of people
that have a lot of silver that they've
inherited over time. Let's start with Do
you want to start with the coins? >>
We'll start with silver. No, we'll talk
That's kind of true. I I that's kind
of shocking really for the guys in the
business. And you don't know what As
they say, what goes up can come down.
>> Sure. >> So, this is where I thought
the folks should might know that if you
should go through your drawers, sometimes
you'll see even your in your drawer um
a flat where there could be one or two
spoons that are sterling. So, what you're
looking for is anything that is marked
uh sterling silver. It'll be on the back.
>> On the back. >> And or on the base of
this and what such you And that is the
American mark. You will have sterling.
On your jewelry, it'll usually say .925
because sterling silver is 925
parts per thousand pure. >> Oh, okay.
>> So, it's not So, it's not completely
pure, but it you know, has a little bit
of alloy. Pieces like the one in your
hand or this spoon here are German
silver and they would have they have 800
fine. So, it's just a little bit less,
but it's still silver. It's still 800
or 80% pure. >> tell that this that this
says sterling silver on it. >> Well, it
doesn't. It says right here. Um And this
is where I realized I left my loop in
the car, right? >> okay. >> Right here,
there's a few little stamps. And Europeans
are really big on I don't know if I
can turn that to where the camera can
see it. Uh right here, there's these
little stamps.
And they're hallmarks. And one will be
the city mark, one will be the date mark,
and one will be the purity mark. And it's
stamped 800. You can't see it on that.
It's easier to see on this spoon here
that it has a little crescent moon,
a little castle, and the word 800. And
that's Ger- That's for Berlin. It's the
mark for Berlin. And it's 800. I have
a whole set. Isn't that pretty? >> It's
gorgeous. So, would you like go to a pawn
shop? Is that where you would go? >> I
would go to um Well, first of all,
you need to figure out what you have.
>> Okay. >> So, you're not walking in
blind, you know, like in front of a
railroad train and and don't kill me. Um
And so, you want to do a little bit of
formula and it's all done by weight. >>
Okay. >> And so, some stuff can actually
be quite a bit. You take
just like this teaspoon
and you put it on this is just a
kitchen scale we put it on and it's 38 g
and we did our little math at at on it
and I've I got a video online under If
you go to YouTube under Gary Germer
there's a video about exactly the
mathematics. I don't want to in case
people haven't had their second cup of
coffee. I don't want to get into
explaining high-end math. >> [laughter]
>> that, Gary.
>> But it's basically um there's a formula
where you convert the troy ounces to
um grams and then you weigh it by the
gram because there's a difference between
troy ounces and imperial ounces. So, you
don't want to use the >> We're going to
put that online so people can make it a
little more understandable for people.
>> And so, with today's silver um I
had it right here at my fingertips.
Um
it's about a dollar I mean $2.22
per gram. >> Okay. >>
And we have 32 g. >> Oh.
>> So, that's >> $71 for this one spoon.
So, if you have a whole set >> Oh, wow.
>> 2 years ago, it's more than tripled
in value in 2 years. So, sets of flatware
2 years ago, it was kind of at a
borderline of people would they spend a
thousand to $1,200 for a set of flatware.
>> Yeah. >> And we were melting some
and some patterns were better than
others. Now, all odds are off. It's now
$3,000 for that same set. >> Wow. >>
And that's where you can have some money
hidden in the drawers. >> Yeah, I love
it. >> One thing I think I want to say
really quickly is um here on these pieces
here, sometimes these are weighted.
Like this has a this has like a a clay
inside of it. >> Yeah, you can feel that.
>> And so, it keeps it from tipping over
is the idea. So, when you weigh it, you
wouldn't just weigh that all the silver.
It has to be taken but it's going to be
mostly. >> Mostly. Okay. And when you
you have some gold examples here, right?
>> Gold is up. Gold is at I just
did it this morning uh 4434.
And that's just all-time high for gold
and it keeps going up as well. And so
even a little tiny nothing broken little
chain like this. Now, I use a kitchen
scale for silver because it it's bulky,
but you might want to invest 20 bucks
into one of these little gold gram
silvers okay cuz they'll go even partial
grams. And so it's a .6 g and
Sorry to be great TV
here to be >> [laughter]
>> I can't remember anything since I
wrote it down a few minutes ago. >> It's
all right. >> [laughter] >> It's
at $70 and and 31 cents. Oops.
71.31
times
.6
>> 42 >> $42 for this little >> that
little thing. >> little thing that might be
just stuck in the crack in your >> Right.
>> Okay, so you know, if you guys are
looking at I would dig it out. This was
a this was a um uh broke it got broken
and had the what do you call it tennis
bracelet but had these really pale
inexpensive stones in it. But this is
all 14 karat and you put that on there.
Now we're talking 11
>> 11.5
>> Yeah. 11.5
times our sev- oops
Whoop. 71.31 >> We don't have much time
left. So that's okay. We know we know
it's a lot Gary. >> It 800 bucks.
>> Oh wow. Oh wow. And then coins?
>> Coins, yes. Pennies as you know, they
quit making them. The date to remember
on pennies is 1982 for 1982 and before
they're pure copper afterwards they're
not. >> Okay. >> Um except during the
war when they made the steel ones. You go
through if you have a big pile of
pennies sift through them and pick out
anything that looks really sharp and
clean and probably the rest but you the
best way of selling them is on eBay
cuz you can't melt them. You can't ruin
American currency. Silver coins are 90%
pure. >> Okay, thank you so much Gary.
This is exciting news. I can't believe it.